<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-02-07T11:06:17-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">All of the Lights</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/piano/2021/02/01/All_of_the_Lights.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="All of the Lights" /><published>2021-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/piano/2021/02/01/All_of_the_Lights</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/piano/2021/02/01/All_of_the_Lights.html">&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Left&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Right&lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;B♭&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;B♭&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;F&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;F&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;F♯ B♭ C♯&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;F♯&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;B♭&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;B♭ C♯ G♯&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;B♭ C♯ F♯&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;B♭ C♯ F&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;C E♭&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;G♯ C E♭&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Left&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Right&lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;B♭      B♭&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;C♯ F B♭&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Left&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Right&lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;F♯ B♭ C♯&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;C♯, F, G♯&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;F♯ A♯ C♯&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;F A♯ C♯&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;C♯&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="piano" /><summary type="html">Left Right B♭ B♭ F F F♯ B♭ C♯ F♯ B♭ B♭ C♯ G♯ B♭ C♯ F♯ B♭ C♯ F C E♭ G♯ C E♭</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tainted Love</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/piano/2021/01/26/Tainted_Love.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tainted Love" /><published>2021-01-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-01-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/piano/2021/01/26/Tainted_Love</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/piano/2021/01/26/Tainted_Love.html">&lt;h3&gt;Db&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;  F&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;    Ab&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;      C&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;        Db&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;          F&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;            Ab&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;              C&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;                Db&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;              C&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;            A♭&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;          F&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;        Db&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;      C&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;   Ab&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;  F&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;C&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;  F&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;    A♭&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;      C&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;        E♭&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;          F&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;            A♭&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;              C&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;                D♭&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;              C&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;            A♭&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;          F&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;        E♭&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;      C&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;    A♭&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;  F&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;B♭&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;  F&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;    A♭&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;      C&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;        D♭&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;          F&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;            A♭&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;              C&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;                E♭&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;              C&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;            A♭&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;          F&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;        D♭&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;      C&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;    A♭&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;  F&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;A♭&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;  F&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;    A♭&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;      C&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;        D♭&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;          E♭&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;            F&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;              A♭&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;                C&lt;/h3&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="piano" /><summary type="html">Db</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Playing with Graph Files</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/11/25/Graph_Files.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Playing with Graph Files" /><published>2020-11-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-11-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/11/25/Graph_Files</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/11/25/Graph_Files.html">&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/media/D3_Maps/Manhattan.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Let's have a go at it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Network Science is the study of two components: nodes and edges. Related nodes are connected by edges and these combinations form a graph. The base of network science is easy to understand but don't be fooled, it is a deeply mathematical field. Network Science PhD programs and deep learning graph libraries have already arrived and there is plenty of room for advances in the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I studied this discipline I had difficulty finding datasets to play with and analyze. This surprised me because a graph files are simple to create and can model a variety of fun relationships. I use Gephi to create graph files by importing a CSV and exporting the resulting output in a format like ___. Data in this format can be accessed by other graph analysis software. The input CSV file is straightforward to create. The cell entries are nodes. Nodes that appear in the same row will have an edge that connects them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main hurdle with making a graph file that is suitable for analysis is not the technical aspect. It lies in finding a subject that lends itself well to the graph format. One of the classic examples is a graph that depicts the relationships between the characters in Victor Hugo's Les Miz. When two characters appear in the same chapter, they are connected by an edge. This works well as a graph file because there are many characters and chapters to create separation. In my first attempts at creating a analyzable graph file there were either too few nodes overall or they all interacted too often so there was no meaningful separations in the graph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some thought I remembered a subject I believed would make for an interesting graph file: the documents of link FOUNDERSLINK. The website archives NUMBER writings of historical American figures from the ____ to ____ era. For the purpose of creating a graph file, I want the correspondance between the founders. This will be a directed graph where the source node is the author and the target node is the recipient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The API page provided a good starting point with the full metadata in JSON format. From here I have creative freedom to extract the relevevant entries and transform them into the CSV format to be used by Gephi.&lt;p&gt;
     
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jchakko/D3_Manhattan&quot;&gt;Link's up!&lt;/a&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Twinkling</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/piano/2020/11/11/Twinkling.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Twinkling" /><published>2020-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/piano/2020/11/11/Twinkling</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/piano/2020/11/11/Twinkling.html">&lt;h3&gt;D♭ F A♭ C D♭ F A♭ C D♭&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;C A♭ F D♭ C A♭ F C&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;F A♭ C E♭ F A♭ C D♭&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;C A♭ F E♭ C A♭ F B♭&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;F A♭ C D♭ F A♭ C E♭&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;C A♭ F D♭ C A♭ F A♭&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;F A♭ C D♭ E♭ F A♭ C&lt;/h3&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="piano" /><summary type="html">D♭ F A♭ C D♭ F A♭ C D♭</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tips for Typing in Malayalam</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/06/14/Malayalam_Keyboarding.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tips for Typing in Malayalam" /><published>2020-06-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-06-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/06/14/Malayalam_Keyboarding</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/06/14/Malayalam_Keyboarding.html">&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/media/D3_Maps/Manhattan.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Let's have a go at it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Malayalam has an elegant alphabet that cannot be confined to a single keyboard. A triple keyboard gets close but even then there are characters that are not inputtable with a single button press. When I first started typing in Malayalam I struggled to find many characters and didn't realize that a lot of them aren't on the keyboard at all. Even with the progress I've made it is still a time consuming process. I can't type with all my fingers, rather I click on characters individually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use a few websites to speed up the process. The first is GOOGLE TRANSLATE which uses a sequence to sequence model to translate betweeen English. It can be fairly reliable for finding the base version of a verb and simple phrase combinations when given an English input. The more accurate method is to provide a Malayalam input and verify that the English translate is reasonable. For that I use OLAM, an English to Malayalam dictionary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will always be an adverb or phrase combination thats too difficult for me to express to a computer. For these cases I turn to manually typing. My keyboard of choice is BRANAH MALAYALAM. I'm sure that native speakers can zip through with this but I was confused as heck the first time I used it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The keyboard has 3 layers. The first layer has vowels on the top left and consonants. The second layer is accessed by clicking shift and the third is accessed by clicking control. A fourth layer can be accessed by clicking shift and control but its empty for Malayalam. This leads me to believe there are languages that have even more characters and I wish their speakers all the best.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stressed consonants and vowels&lt;/p&gt;

https://jilljuck.com/funny-malayalam-jokes
     
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jchakko/D3_Manhattan&quot;&gt;Link's up!&lt;/a&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cleric Spells</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/06/06/Selenium.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cleric Spells" /><published>2020-06-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-06-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/06/06/Selenium</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/06/06/Selenium.html">&lt;p&gt;Clerics are awesome. They can fill many roles and playstyles from backline to the front. I had trouble finding my footing when I first started playing because I had some misconceptions about what a cleric should do. While clerics have the ability to heal it isn't a good use of tempo. On one turn I can heal about 8 HP which isn't helpful when my paladin is getting hit for 26 damage. Once I realized what the better spells are I realized how powerful clerics truly are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Cantrips&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cantrips can be cast an unlimited number of times. They can't be changed so its very easy to get stuck with a bunch of bad ones. Even if thats the situation you're stuck in, eventually you'll get a 4th one and you can pick up Guidance. It's too powerful to pass up. Guidance lets people roll a d4 when doing an ability check. A lot of things require ability checks like jumping chasms, lockpicking, persuasion. I spam guidance out of combat because.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like the idea of Thaumaturgy but it rarely sees use. My DM Ricardo runs a flavorful campaign and I always look for opportunities to act a fool and even then its hard to find usage for it. Spare the Dying is outclassed by a level 1 spell called Healing Word. The last cantrip I have is Sacred Flame which is basically a normal hit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Proaction Over Reaction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like I said earlier, healing damage that has already been dealt is not a good use of time. Its better to prevent the damage from happening in the first place. This makes Bless a very powerful cleric spell. It grants 3 creatures an extra d4 dice on attack rolls and saving throws. Simply put it makes the party more accurate when attacking and more likely to avoid harmful effects. This spell stands head and shoulder over the other level one options for a few reasons. It works on 3 players, it doesn't have some prerequesite for the d4 to be rolled, and it does not disappear when the target attacks. Bless is so powerful that I build my strategy around this spell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Focus Your Mind&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few different spell cast types. Bless is concentration. Concentration spells break when casting another concentration spell or failing a constitution save after taking damage. Since I want bless up all the time I stay strapped with non concentration spells. Some good options are Healing Word, Guiding Bolt, Inflict Wounds, Aid, and Sanctuary. Healing Word is as bonus action that can ressurect people from a distance. Guiding Bolt deals damage and makes the next hit against the same target more accurate. Inflict wounds is 3d10s of nectrotic damage and Aid gives a session long HP increase to multiple party members. Sanctuary makes an ally harder to hit which in theory can be combined with other dodge improvements to make a friend unhittable. Then there's Spiritual Weapon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spiritual Weapon is a bonus cast spell that creats a floating, movable weapon as a bonus action. It only takes one spell slot to cast then it can be used to melee attack from long range as a bonus action. It does not interfere with Bless, its empowered by it. This combined with ordinary attacking puts out some real damage. It also makes playing more fun. My party does not have a strong front line. Discovering this spell made me realize that I can stand in the front and fight. After the mace comes the spiritual mace and with Bless, both are going to hit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;A Life Beyond Bless&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bless is not the end all be all Cleric spell. Even if it was it would get boring to cast all of the time. In future sessions I'm looking cast Silence and Spirit Guardians as soon as I get 3rd Level Spells. Silence wrecks other spellcasters because most spells have a speaking component. Spirit Guardians slows and batters enemies around the caster. There was a time when I healed as a Cleric, now I don't have the time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">Clerics are awesome. They can fill many roles and playstyles from backline to the front. I had trouble finding my footing when I first started playing because I had some misconceptions about what a cleric should do. While clerics have the ability to heal it isn't a good use of tempo. On one turn I can heal about 8 HP which isn't helpful when my paladin is getting hit for 26 damage. Once I realized what the better spells are I realized how powerful clerics truly are.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/media/D3_Maps/Manhattan.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/media/D3_Maps/Manhattan.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A Simple BeautifulSoup Example</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/22/Beautiful_Soup.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Simple BeautifulSoup Example" /><published>2020-05-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-05-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/22/Beautiful_Soup</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/22/Beautiful_Soup.html">&lt;p&gt;There is so much data available on the internet - even if it isn't always in an analysis friendly format. The results of any modern sports tournament are hosted somewhere. Countless blog posts and movie reviews are available to the public free of charge. This information can be extracted programmatically allowing researchers to build large datasets without tedious manual input.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crummy.com/software/BeautifulSoup/bs4/doc/&quot;&gt;BeautifulSoup&lt;/a&gt; is a web scraper Python library that makes it a snap to request HTML pages and parse the information on them. With a few short loops, information hosted on a web page is organized into a luxurious CSV or JSON file. Scraping a set of web pages has 2 parts: how do I extract the information on an individual page and how do I get the set of pages to parse from?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; It comes down to pattern recognition and using the element inspector. The user score could have its own div. The URLs of each page may only differ by a date or city name. Better yet, there could be a page that contains the URL for every episode of a TV series. Each situation is going to be different so let's take a look at a simple use case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Collecting a list of National Parks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this example I am going to scrape the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nps.gov&quot;&gt;National Park Service&lt;/a&gt; website to create a dictionary of all listed parks and their individual URLs. I start by extracting the information from a single page with the assumption that most of the pages will have the same format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/media/BeautifulSoup/Vermont.png&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Vermont's Park Service Page&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The orange boxes show the indvidual entries and the green box is a container that holds all of them. Now its time to use the page inspector to find a way for BeautifulSoup to parse these locations. The green box has id=&quot;parkListResultsArea&quot;. The orange boxes are links surrounded by h3 tags within the parkListResultsArea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Extract parks from Vermont's page&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
  &lt;code&gt;
    from bs4 import BeautifulSoup
    import requests

    url = &quot;https://www.nps.gov/state/vt/index.htm&quot;
    soup = BeautifulSoup(requests.get(url).content)

    vermont = soup.find(id = &quot;parkListResultsArea&quot;)
    parks = vermont.find_all('h3')

    for park in parks:
        link = park.find('a')
        print(link.get_text())
  &lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Output&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
  &lt;code&gt;
    Appalachian
    Marsh - Billings - Rockefeller
    North Country
  &lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scraper returns the desired information from a single page. Now let's expand the code to retrieve information from multiple pages. I created a function that takes a url and executes the scraping logic. With a simple loop I can call the function for multiple states. I also added a function that takes the information from each park and transforms it into a dictionary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Helper Functions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
  &lt;code&gt;
    # Retrieve all parks from a state's page
    def parse_state(url):
        soup = BeautifulSoup(requests.get(url).content)
        state = soup.find(id = &quot;parkListResultsArea&quot;)
        parks = state.find_all('h3')
        return parks

    # Transfrom a BeautifulSoup tag to a dictionary of park information
    def parse_park(park, state):
        tag = park.find('a')
        url = tag['href']
        name = tag.get_text()
        park_dict = {&quot;Name&quot;: name, &quot;State&quot;: state, &quot;URL&quot;: url}
        return park_dict
  &lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Main&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
  &lt;code&gt;	

    # Full results container
    results = []

    url = &quot;https://www.nps.gov/state/PLACEHOLDER/index.htm&quot;
    states = [&quot;vt&quot;, &quot;de&quot;, &quot;wi&quot;]

    # For every state in the above list
    for state in states:
        # Retrieve all parks from the state's page
        state_url = url.replace(&quot;PLACEHOLDER&quot;, state)
        state_results = parse_state(state_url)
    
        # For every park in the state's page
        for park in state_results:
            # Transform the BeautifulSoup tag to a dictionary of park information
            park_result = parse_park(park, state)
            results.append(park_result)
  &lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each state park on the Vermont, Delaware, and Wisconsin pages have been recorded in a dictionary. All such dictionaries are stored in a list called results. This is a format that is easy to transform into a CSV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Write list of dictionaries to CSV&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
  &lt;code&gt;
    import csv
    with open('export.csv', 'w', encoding='utf-8', newline='') as output_file:
        writer = csv.DictWriter(output_file, fieldnames=results[0].keys())
        writer.writeheader()
        writer.writerows(results)  
  &lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/media/BeautifulSoup/Export.png&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Huzzah! A Comma Separated Values file!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BeautifulSoup is a great tool for pulling information from HTML files. Often, the questions that I want answered need a dataset that hasn't been organized so I should get used to building them myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crummy.com/software/BeautifulSoup/bs4/doc/&quot;&gt;BeautifulSoup Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jchakko/BeautifulSoup&quot;&gt;GitHub Repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">There is so much data available on the internet - even if it isn't always in an analysis friendly format. The results of any modern sports tournament are hosted somewhere. Countless blog posts and movie reviews are available to the public free of charge. This information can be extracted programmatically allowing researchers to build large datasets without tedious manual input.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cleric Spells</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/06/Cleric_Spells.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cleric Spells" /><published>2020-05-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-05-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/06/Cleric_Spells</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/05/06/Cleric_Spells.html">&lt;p&gt;Clerics are awesome. They can fill many roles and playstyles from backline to the front. I had trouble finding my footing when I first started playing because I had some misconceptions about what a cleric should do. While clerics have the ability to heal it isn't a good use of tempo. On one turn I can heal about 8 HP which isn't helpful when my paladin is getting hit for 26 damage. Once I realized what the better spells are I realized how powerful clerics truly are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Cantrips&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cantrips can be cast an unlimited number of times. They can't be changed so its very easy to get stuck with a bunch of bad ones. Even if thats the situation you're stuck in, eventually you'll get a 4th one and you can pick up Guidance. It's too powerful to pass up. Guidance lets people roll a d4 when doing an ability check. A lot of things require ability checks like jumping chasms, lockpicking, persuasion. I spam guidance out of combat because.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like the idea of Thaumaturgy but it rarely sees use. My DM Ricardo runs a flavorful campaign and I always look for opportunities to act a fool and even then its hard to find usage for it. Spare the Dying is outclassed by a level 1 spell called Healing Word. The last cantrip I have is Sacred Flame which is basically a normal hit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Proaction Over Reaction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like I said earlier, healing damage that has already been dealt is not a good use of time. Its better to prevent the damage from happening in the first place. This makes Bless a very powerful cleric spell. It grants 3 creatures an extra d4 dice on attack rolls and saving throws. Simply put it makes the party more accurate when attacking and more likely to avoid harmful effects. This spell stands head and shoulder over the other level one options for a few reasons. It works on 3 players, it doesn't have some prerequesite for the d4 to be rolled, and it does not disappear when the target attacks. Bless is so powerful that I build my strategy around this spell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Focus Your Mind&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few different spell cast types. Bless is concentration. Concentration spells break when casting another concentration spell or failing a constitution save after taking damage. Since I want bless up all the time I stay strapped with non concentration spells. Some good options are Healing Word, Guiding Bolt, Inflict Wounds, Aid, and Sanctuary. Healing Word is as bonus action that can ressurect people from a distance. Guiding Bolt deals damage and makes the next hit against the same target more accurate. Inflict wounds is 3d10s of nectrotic damage and Aid gives a session long HP increase to multiple party members. Sanctuary makes an ally harder to hit which in theory can be combined with other dodge improvements to make a friend unhittable. Then there's Spiritual Weapon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spiritual Weapon is a bonus cast spell that creats a floating, movable weapon as a bonus action. It only takes one spell slot to cast then it can be used to melee attack from long range as a bonus action. It does not interfere with Bless, its empowered by it. This combined with ordinary attacking puts out some real damage. It also makes playing more fun. My party does not have a strong front line. Discovering this spell made me realize that I can stand in the front and fight. After the mace comes the spiritual mace and with Bless, both are going to hit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;A Life Beyond Bless&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bless is not the end all be all Cleric spell. Even if it was it would get boring to cast all of the time. In future sessions I'm looking cast Silence and Spirit Guardians as soon as I get 3rd Level Spells. Silence wrecks other spellcasters because most spells have a speaking component. Spirit Guardians slows and batters enemies around the caster. There was a time when I healed as a Cleric, now I don't have the time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">Clerics are awesome. They can fill many roles and playstyles from backline to the front. I had trouble finding my footing when I first started playing because I had some misconceptions about what a cleric should do. While clerics have the ability to heal it isn't a good use of tempo. On one turn I can heal about 8 HP which isn't helpful when my paladin is getting hit for 26 damage. Once I realized what the better spells are I realized how powerful clerics truly are.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/media/D3_Maps/Manhattan.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/media/D3_Maps/Manhattan.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Automating the Pipeline for a Slowly Evolving Network</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/04/12/Automating_Network_Pipline.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Automating the Pipeline for a Slowly Evolving Network" /><published>2020-04-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/04/12/Automating_Network_Pipline</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/04/12/Automating_Network_Pipline.html">&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/media/D3_Maps/Germany_Roads.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Piece of Me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update the adjacency list&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create the new layout using Gephi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add new nodes to data.json&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add new links to data.json&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use D3 to drag and drop new layout&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use SVG element to update data.json&lt;/p&gt;
     
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jchakko/Ultimate_Finals&quot;&gt;Skid&lt;/a&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/media/D3_Maps/Germany_Roads.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/media/D3_Maps/Germany_Roads.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Let’s Natural Language Process an Agglutinative Language</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/03/15/D3_Malayalam_Word_Frequency.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Let's Natural Language Process an Agglutinative Language" /><published>2020-03-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-03-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/03/15/D3_Malayalam_Word_Frequency</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2020/03/15/D3_Malayalam_Word_Frequency.html">&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/media/D3_Maps/Germany_Roads.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;D3.js is a powerful data visualization library that displays graphics right in your browser. It can consume geographic information which is widely available these days. With some additional data, D3 can make compelling geovisualizations like choropleths, and dot density maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Preparing the Data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of spatial data that is free to use on the internet. For this post I am using the free country level data provided by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.diva-gis.org/gdata&quot;&gt;DIVA-GIS.&lt;/a&gt; Spatial data is often separated into a few components then compressed into a zip file. D3 cannot work with the data in this format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully there are tools online that convert spatial data zip files to GeoJSON, a format that is D3 friendly. My go to is &lt;a href=&quot;https://mapshaper.org/&quot;&gt;Mapshaper&lt;/a&gt;. Import the entire zip file. Mapshaper has a simplify feature which makes the file smaller but the lines less precise. I like to play with it and pretend I'm making minimalist art or something. Anyways when you're finished export the data as a GeoJSON file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Display the Spatial Data&lt;/h2&gt;   

&lt;p&gt;Projections make it possible to display a 3D object on a 2D surface. There are a handful of projections each with their strengths and differences. GeoJSON coordinates can be transformed by a projection function then displayed using a line generator.&lt;/p&gt;
     
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jchakko/Ultimate_Finals&quot;&gt;Get the GML file from my Git Hub&lt;/a&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/media/D3_Maps/Germany_Roads.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/media/D3_Maps/Germany_Roads.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>